The Nemours Papers: Series 3 of the Du Pont Family Papers 1831 (1915-1935) 1947
Special Collections, Washington and Lee University
Special Collections and Archives, James G. Leyburn Library, Washington and Lee University
Nemours Papers: Series 3 of the duPont Family Papers 1831 (1915-1935) 1947
Special Collections and Archives, James G. Leyburn Library, Washington and Lee University
WLU Coll. 0169
Fifteen linear feet of records. 15 linear feet
Administrative Information
Access
There are no restrictions.
Provenance
The Alfred I. duPont Nemours papers consist of those duPont manuscripts which were maintained at Nemours, the family estate in Wilmington, Delaware. At some point they were shipped to the offices of the Jessie Ball duPont Religious, Charitable and Educational Fund in Jacksonville, Florida. As designated by Jessie Ball duPont in her will, the Nemours papers were donated to Washington and Lee University, along with the duPont family papers located in Jacksonville. Because of their distinct provenance it was decided to process the papers from Nemours as a separate collection rather than integrating them into the Alfred I. duPont Jacksonville papers or into the Jessie Ball duPont Papers.
Scope and Content Information
The Nemours Papers are part of the duPont Family Collection and consist of 15 linear feet of records dating from 1831 to 1947. The bulk of the material dates from 1915 to 1935 and reflects the business, financial, and family affairs of Alfred I. duPont (1864-1935). In addition, the Papers include some of the records of Alfred's second wife, Alicia Bradford Maddox duPont (1875-1920), and his third wife, Jessie Ball duPont (1884-1970).
Document types include personal and business correspondence, as well as legal documents, which relate primarily to patents and to several lawsuits in which Alfred I. duPont was involved. Business and financial records relate to family matters, such as Alfred I. duPont's guardianship of Alicia Amory Maddox, as well as to professional interests such as mining. The Papers include printed materials, such as clippings, pamphlets, and magazine articles. They also contain a large number of photographs documenting the family and social lives of Alfred I. and Jessie Ball duPont.
The Alfred I. duPont Nemours Papers have been arranged as six series: Correspondence, Business and Financial Records, Legal Records, General, Printed Materials, and Photographs.
Organization
Series I: CORRESPONDENCE, 1845-1947 (3 linear feet)
This series consists primarily of the correspondence of Alfred I. duPont, but it also includes some of the correspondence of his wives Alicia Bradford Maddox duPont and Jessie Ball duPont. Consequently, the series has been arranged alphabetically by these three individuals.
Alfred's business affairs are documented in his correspondence with merchants and manufacturers, as well as in his correspondence with duPont managers such as Edward Ball. Family and personal affairs are reflected in Alfred's correspondence with family members such as brother Maurice duPont and sister Marguerite duPont Lee. Alfred's main personal correspondents are his daughter Madeleine Hiebler in Munich, Germany, and his wife Jessie.
The series also documents aspects of Alfred I. duPont's charitable giving. Recipients of contributions represented in this series include the American Committee for Devastated France, the welfare home of Smyrna, Delaware, and Reverend H.M. Bartlett of Christ Church in Wilmington.
Correspondence of or relating to Alicia Bradford Maddox duPont consist primarily of exchanges with her mother Eleuthera duPont Bradford. In addition, there are several files of condolence letters to Alfred following Alicia's death in 1920. Letters of sympathy after Alfred's death in 1935 constitute the correspondence of Jessie Ball duPont.
SERIES II: BUSINESS AND FINANCIAL RECORDS, 1831-1933 (4 linear feet)
This series contains receipts, invoices, correspondence, agreements, account books, and ledgers which document the business and financial affiars of Alfred I. duPont. In addition, the series includes three of Alicia Bradford Maddox duPont's check books and four cancelled checks written by her father, Edward Bradford. The series is arranged alphabetically by document type such as "check books" and by subjects such as "guardianship for Alicia Amory Maddox."
The business interest documented in the greatest detail in this series is mining. Included are correspondence, an account book, and agreements which give evidence of Alfred's involvement in Colorado mines and the Great Falls mine in the years 1912 through 1919. Alfred's general financial situation is best documented in his income tax records and his financial statements for the years 1913 through 1928.
After wife Alicia's death in 1920, Alfred assumed guardianship over Alicia's daughter by George Maddox, Alicia Amory Maddox. This series reflects Alfred's responsibilities as trustee of Alicia's finances. Included are invoices of Alicia's purchases and expenses to be paid by Alfred, as well as Alfred's annual guardian statements and income tax returns for Alicia's property.
Finally, this series contains a large number of invoices, payroll records, and receipts for Alfred's yachting expenses.
SERIES III: LEGAL RECORDS, 1838-1947 (1.75 linear feet)
This series includes transcripts of court hearings, correspondence, patents, financial agreements, and wills which have been arranged alphabetically by subject.
The main topics addressed in this series are the estate of Alicia Bradford Maddox duPont; the lawsuit Philip F. duPont et al. versus Pierre S. duPont et al.; and Alfred's divorce from his first wife, Bessie Gardner duPont.
Other issues documented in less detail include Alfred's appointment as guardian of Alicia Amory Maddox in 1920 and his release in 1924; the divorce of Alicia Bradford Maddox and George Maddox in 1907; and the child custody case between Alicia and Harold S. Glendening over their son Alan in 1940.
SERIES IV: GENERAL, 1921-1928 (0.25 linear foot)
Arranged alphabetically by subject, this series documents the construction and furnishing of Alfred I. duPont's properties Cherry Island, Maryland, and White Eagle, Long Island, New York. Included are correspondence with architects, and reports specifiying the work at the two properties including lists of furniture for the main residence as will as the servants' quarters.
This series also reflects Alfred's involvement with the Washington Bridge Commission in Wilmington. Included are his correspondence as chairman of the commission, a copy of the executed contract, and a newspaper clipping on the dedication of the Washinton Street Memorial Bridge.
SERIES V: PRINTED MATERIAL, 1909-1940 (1 linear foot)
This series consists of articles; loose clippings; five scrapbooks of clippings; and a leatherbound volume of two issues of Town and Country from 1913 featuring an article regarding Nemours. Several of the loose publications and a scrapbook with clippings on radium ore reflect Alfred I. duPont's scientific interests. Other topics addressed include society news; the affairs of distant duPont relatives; Alfred and Jessie Ball duPont's charitable giving; the donation of a bust of President tyler to the State Captiol in Richmond, Virginia; Delaware politics; the banking business; and Alfred's death in 1935.
SERIES VI: PHOTOGRAPHS (5 linear feet)
This series consists of photographs of Alfred I. duPont and Jessie Ball duPont, as well as photographs of members of the Ball and duPont families. Also included are photographs of distant relatives, friends, and acquaintances of Jessie Ball duPont. Other photographic topics include the duPont properties Cherry Island, White Eagle, and Epping forest; the duPont yachts; travels; and several duPont businesses such as mills and the St. Joe Paper Company.
This series has been arranged alphabetically by the individuals and subjects depicted on the photographs.
Contents List
- Correspondence
  - Alfred I. duPont
    - Correspondence with daughter Madeleine Hiebler 1920 (Box-folder 1:1)
    - Letter from William Jervey to E.G. Bradford 1837 January 27 (Box-folder 1:2)
    - Letter from William Jervey to E.G. Bradford 1845 July 1 (Box-folder 1:3)
    - Christmas Card n.d. (Box-folder 1:4)
    - Correspondence with family members including siblings Maurice duPont and Marguerite Lee, and son Alfred Victor; topics include old age pension 1927-1930 (Box-folder 1:5)
    - Coleman duPont 1902-1911 (Box-folder 1:6)
    - General correspondence; Marguerite Lee, Margery duPont, several journalists 1916-1922 (Box-folder 1:7)
    - Correspondence re: newspaper articles on labor relations, includes a clipping and a release on "Fair Play" 1917 (Box-folder 1:8)
    - Letters to Jessie Ball duPont 1921 (Box-folder 1:9)
    - Brown Bros. & Co. re: interest payments 1928 (Box-folder 1:10)
    - Extract of a letter from Dorothy Lee, contains also a list of the children of "cousin James" 1928, n.d. (Box-folder 1:11)
    - Personal and business correspondence 1929 (Box-folder 1:12)
    - Correspondence re; lightening rods 1930 (Box-folder 1:14)
    - Requests for charity, re: assistance to William Horty 1931 (Box-folder 1:15)
    - Elizabeth Dorman re: rental of the Henry Clay property 1931-32 (Box-folder 1:16)
    - Notes and correspondence by Marguis James, author of Alfred I. duPont-Family Rebel, re: research for the biography of duPont 1940-1941 (Box-folder 1:17)
    - Correspondence between Jessie Ball duPont and William A. Martin re: property in Alhambra, California 1933 (Box-folder 1:18)
    - American Committee for Devastated France 1918-1919 (Box-folder 1:19)
    - French document n.d. (Box-folder 1:20)
    - J.L. Dashiell; toast at the wedding of Sarah and Irvine Dickey 1908-1924 (Box-folder 1:21)
    - Robert Miller 1912 (Box-folder 1:22)
    - J. Edmund Thompson 1912 (Box-folder 1:23)
    - William A. Glasgow 1917-1920 (Box-folder 1:24)
    - William A. Glasgow 1919 (Box-folder 1:25)
    - Rebecca Harding 1919 (Box-folder 1:26)
    - Personal correspondence 1920-1934 (Box-folder 1:27)
    - Madeleine Hiebler 1921 (Box-folder 2:1)
    - Membership card of the Gibson Island Club 1922 (Box-folder 2:2)
    - James B. Gilmer 1922 (Box-folder 2:3)
    - Denise duPont 1927 (Box-folder 2:4)
    - Business correspondence; correspondents include Cartier, Cadillac 1927-1928 (Box-folder 2:5)
    - Merchants and other sales people 1928 (Box-folder 2:6)
    - Jessie Ball duPont 1929 (Box-folder 2:7)
    - Ruth G. Thomas 1931 (Box-folder 2:8)
    - Mail orders for wardrobe 1931 (Box-folder 2:9)
    - Invitations n.d. (Box-folder 2:10)
    - Telegram n.d. (Box-folder 2:11)
    - Telegram n.d. (Box-folder 2:12)
    - Merchants and Manufacturers 1920 (Box-folder 2:13)
    - Charles W. Mills re: financial matters 1920-1922 (Box-folder 2:14)
    - Robert Pennington re: financial matters 1921 (Box-folder 2:15)
    - Pro-Ton-O Concentrated Foods 1925 (Box-folder 2:16)
    - General correspondence mainly re: business matter; I.D. Shor 1919-1930 (Box-folder 2:17)
    - General correspondence; correspondents include Frank Allee and George T. Maxwell 1930 (Box-folder 2:18)
    - George T. Maxwell 1930 (Box-folder 2:19)
    - Baker P. Lee 1929-1934 (Box-folder 2:20)
    - Gavin's Detective Agency 1930-1931 (Box-folder 3:1)
    - Proposals for a radio system for a welfare home in Smyrna, Delaware 1933 (Box-folder 3:2)
    - Correspondence and brochures re: a radio system n.d. (Box-folder 3:3)
    - Sand Dollars 1947 (Box-folder 3:4)
    - Re: a subsidy for Reverand H.M. Bartlett of Christ Church n.d. (Box-folder 3:5)
    - Edward Ball 1933 September-October (Box-folder 3:6)
    - Edward Ball 1933 November-December (Box-folder 3:7)
    - Edward Ball 1934 January-April (Box-folder 3:8)
    - Edward Ball 1934 May-September (Box-folder 3:9)
    - Edward Ball 1934 October-December (Box-folder 3:10)
  - Alicia Bradford Maddox duPont
    - Eleuthera Paulina duPont Bradford 1885-1904 (Box-folder 4:1)
    - Eleuthera Bradford 1890, 1904-1905, n.d. (Box-folder 4:2)
    - Mainly correspondence with Eleuthera Bradford 1896-1904, n.d. (Box-folder 4:3)
    - Eleuthera Bradford 1901-1905, n.d. (Box-folder 4:4)
    - Eleuthera Bradford 1904-1905, n.d. (Box-folder 4:5)
    - Eleuthera Bradford 1903-1905, n.d. (Box-folder 4:6)
    - General correspondence 1920 (Box-folder 5:1)
    - Sympathy letters re: Alicia duPont's death 1920 (Box-folder 5:2-8)
  - Jessie Ball duPont
    - Sympathy letters re: death of AId 1935 (Box-folder 5:9-11)
    - Sympathy letters 1935 (Box-folder 6:1-5)
    - Telegrams re: death of AId 1935 (Box-folder 6:6-7)
    - Sympathy letters 1935 (Box-folder 7:1-2)
- Financial and Business Records
  - Checks and checkbooks
    - Four cancelled checks written by Edward Bradford 1898-1900 (Box-folder 7:3)
    - Title Guarantee and Trust Co. checkbook, Alicia duPont 1915-1919 (Box-folder 7:4)
    - Delaware Trust Co. checkbook, Alicia duPont 1917-1920 (Box-folder 7:5)
    - Girard Trust Co. checkbook, Alicia duPont 1917-1918 (Box-folder 7:6)
  - Colorado-Gilpin Gold and Radium Mining Co.
    - Geological Atlas of Colorado Mines 1905, very fragile (Box-folder 8:1)
    - Correspondence, topics include the stocks of the Colorado-Gilpin Mining Co. 1912-1918 (Box-folder 8:2)
    - Correspondence re: the value of the German-Belcher Mine; Wood & Mitchell leases 1913-1916 (Box-folder 8:3)
    - Wood Mine lease 1913 (Box-folder 8:4)
    - Correspondence re: the German-Belcher Co. 1913-1914 (Box-folder 8:5)
    - Correspondence re: Colorado-Gilpin and German-Belcher mines 1914-1916 (Box-folder 8:6)
    - Mining deed and correspondence; includes the minutes of a special stockholders meeting of the United Gold and Uranium Co. 1914-1922 (Box-folder 8:7)
    - Correspondence re: the Colorado-Gilpin Mining Co. and United Gold and Uranium Mining Co. 1915 (Box-folder 8:8)
    - Correspondence, lease of the Colorado-Gilpin Mining Co. 1915-1919 (Box-folder 8:9)
    - Rockdale mining lease and correspondence 1916 (Box-folder 8:10)
    - Correspondence re: pitchblende, Colorado-Gilpin Mining Co. 1916-1919 (Box-folder 8:11)
    - Correspondence with William Wright, president of the Colorado-Gilpin Co. 1916 (Box-folder 8:12)
    - Correspondence re: Colorado-Gilpin Mining Co. 1916-1917 (Box-folder 8:13)
    - Telegram 1917 (Box-folder 8:14)
    - Letter 1918 (Box-folder 8:15)
    - Partial letter to stockholders n.d. (Box-folder 8:16)
    - Publications re: mining, "Excavation and recovery of Radium, Uranium and Vandium from Carnotite," maps of Illinois and New York City 1913, n.d. (Box-folder 8:17)
  - General
    - Balance of the National City Development Co. 1922 (Box-folder 9:1)
    - Charles I. duPont, receipt for purchase of four shares of the Wilmington Fire Insurance Co. 1933 (Box-folder 9:2)
    - Receipt, portion of a letter from Madeleine Hiebler to Mary Brereton 1923 (Box-folder 9:3)
    - Stock and bond records 1916 (Box-folder 9:4)
    - French-American Constructive Corp.: option agreement 1919 (Box-folder 9:5)
    - French-American Constructive Corp.: stock certificate 1919 (Box-folder 9:6)
    - H.R. Harding: financial agreement and other documents re: a patent for a tomato skinning and coring device 1921 (Box-folder 9:7)
    - Delaware Title Insurance Co., bond and stock agreements 1922 (Box-folder 9:8)
    - Safe deposit receipt 1922 (Box-folder 9:9)
    - Ritz-Carlton Hotel receipt 1920 (Box-folder 9:10)
    - Records relating to a reorganization of the black powder department and to a profit sharing plan for the DuPont Co. 1911 (Box-folder 9:11)
    - Powder chart, undated; program of an entertainment of the Seaman's Orphanage, New York 1889 (Box-folder 9:12)
    - Great Falls Mine: account book 1915-1916 (Box-folder 9:13)
  - Guardianship for Alicia Armory Maddox
    - Credit Lyonnais stub book, M.A. Trip n.d. (Box-folder 9:14)
    - Credit Lyonnais stub book, M.A. Trip n.d. (Box-folder 9:15)
    - Invoices, receipts, and cancelled checks for bills paid through Miss Harriet Hibbard 1918-1919 (Box-folder 9:16)
    - Invoices, receipts, and cancelled checks for bills paid through Miss Harriet Hibbard 1918-1919 (Box-folder 10:1-2)
    - Guardian statements 1920 (Box-folder 10:3)
    - Guardian account of AId, records of the Credit Lyonnais 1920, n.d. (Box-folder 10:4)
    - Guardian vouchers 1921 (Box-folder 10:5-6)
    - Guardian account, Delaware Trust Co. 1921 (Box-folder 10:7)
    - Guardian statements and receipts 1920-1921 (Box-folder 10:8)
    - Guardian statement for the expenses of Alicia Armory Maddox 1921 (Box-folder 10:9)
    - Invoices and receipts for expenses of Alicia Armory Maddox 1921 (Box-folder 10:10)
    - Invoices and receipts for expenses of Alicia Armory Maddox 1921 (Box-folder 11:1-3)
    - Delaware Trust Co. checkbook containing checkstubs of expenses for Alicia Armory Maddox, such as income tax and salary for governess 1921-1925 (Box-folder 11:4)
    - Guardian statement 1921 (Box-folder 11:5)
    - Invoices and cancelled checks for the expenses of Alicia Armory Maddox and husband Harold S. Glendening 1921-1923 (Box-folder 11:6)
    - Guardian statement 1922 (Box-folder 11:7)
    - Invoices and receipts for the expenses of Alicia Armory Maddox 1920-1922 (Box-folder 11:8-9)
    - Guardian account statements 1922 (Box-folder 12:1)
    - Invoices and receipts for expenses of Alicia Armory Maddox during her stay in London 1922 (Box-folder 12:2)
    - Income tax 1923-1924 (Box-folder 12:3)
    - Guardian statement 1923 (Box-folder 12:4)
    - Invoices and receipts for expenses of Alicia Armory Maddox 1923-1924 (Box-folder 12:5)
    - Guardian statements 1924 (Box-folder 12:6)
  - Ledgers
    - Ledger 1831-1832, in advanced state of deterioration-VERY FRAGILE (Box-folder 12:7)
    - National City Development Co., account book 1922 (Box-folder 12:8)
  - Taxes, Financial Statements, and Reports
    - AId income tax returns 1913-1914 (Box-folder 13:1)
    - AId and Alicia duPont, income tax returns 1917 (Box-folder 13:2)
    - Tax information 1918-1925 (Box-folder 13:3)
    - AId income tax return 1920 (Box-folder 13:4)
    - Sundry expenses [1920?] (Box-folder 13:5)
    - AId income tax return 1921 (Box-folder 13:6)
    - AId financial records 1922-1923 (Box-folder 13:7)
    - AId income tax return 1923 (Box-folder 13:8)
    - AId financial statements 1922-1928 (Box-folder 13:9)
    - AId tax information 1925 (Box-folder 13:10)
    - AId financial statement 1925-1926 (Box-folder 13:11)
    - AId CPA reports 1926-1928 (Box-folder 13:12)
    - AId financial statements 1927-1928 (Box-folder 13:13-18)
    - Almours Securities Inc., CPA report 1928 (Box-folder 13:19)
    - Alicia duPont income tax return 1918 (Box-folder 13:20)
    - Jessie Ball duPont tax information 1925 (Box-folder 13:21)
  - Yacht
    - Yacht statements 1924 (Box-folder 14:1-2)
    - Yacht statements 1926 (Box-folder 14:3-5)
    - Yacht hardware receipts 1933 (Box-folder 14:6)
    - Nenemoosha yachting expenses, include payroll records and receipts for food, supplies, laundry, hotel, etc. 1924-1925 (Box-folder 14:7-8)
    - Yachting expenses 1925-1926 (Box-folder 15:1-11)
    - Yachting expenses 1929 (Box-folder 15:12)
    - Correspondence with Carlisle & Finch Co. re: search lights for the Nenemoosha 1928 (Box-folder 15:13)
- Legal Records
  - Estate of Alicia Maddox duPont
    - Will of Alicia Maddox duPont 1919 (Box-folder 16:1)
    - Tursteeship of will of Alicia Maddox duPont 1921 (Box-folder 16:2-4)
    - Delaware Trust Co. re: the settlement of the estate of Alicia Maddox duPont 1922 (Box-folder 16:5)
    - Delaware Trust Co. and DuPont Co. re: settlement of the estate of Alicia Maddox duPont 1922 (Box-folder 16:6)
    - Estate inventory, undated transcript of the Surrogate's Court of Nassau County, New York, re: the taxation of the estate 1920, n.d. (Box-folder 16:7)
    - Estate inventory n.d. (Box-folder 16:8)
    - Rental of land owned by the estate of Alicia Maddox duPont to Jessie Ball duPont 1924 (Box-folder 16:9)
  - General
    - Appointment as guardian of Alicia Armory Maddox, and release from guardianship 1920-1924 (Box-folder 16:10)
    - Includes a deed for the Broom Street property, correspondence with George Davis, lawyer 1923-1924 (Box-folder 16:11)
    - Will of Ida von Frantzius 1930 (Box-folder 16:12)
  - Lawsuits
    - District Court of the United States for the District of Delaware, Philip F. duPont et al, v. Pierre S. duPont et al., records of the final hearing, vol. III 1916 (Box-folder 16:13)
    - United States Circuit Court, Philip F. duPont et al. v. Pierre S. duPont et al., appeal from the District Court of the United States for the District of Delaware, brief of appellants 1918 (Box-folder 16:14)
    - Charles Hudgins Jr. v. Mrs. F.B. Crowninshield, Harry duPont, and David T. Marvel 1930 (Box-folder 17:1)
    - Correspondence re: the suit Philip F. duPont et al. v. Pierre S. duPont et al., also re: stockholders of the duPont company 1916-1917 (Box-folder 17:2)
    - Correspondence re: the lawsuit Philip F. duPont et al. v. Pierre S. duPont et al. 1918-1919 (Box-folder 17:3)
    - Divorce decree for Alicia Bradford Maddox and George Armory Maddox [1917] 1939 (Box-folder 17:4)
    - Divorce suit Alfred I. duPont v. Bessie G. duPont: testimony of Marguerite duPont Lee, Ellen M. LaMotte, George Quintard Horwitz, and Rebecca Z. Abbott on behalf of AId 1906 (Box-folder 17:5)
    - Financial agreement between AId and Bessie Gardner duPont 1905 (Box-folder 17:6)
    - Appellate Division of the Supreme Court, Harold S. Glendening v. Alicia Armory Maddox Glendening re: custody over son Alan, brief on behalf of Alicia Glendening 1940 (Box-folder 17:7)
  - Patents
    - Manufacture of gunpowder 1838-1845 (Box-folder 17:8)
    - Composition for blasting powder 1900-1903 (Box-folder 17:9)
    - Lawyer E.G. Siggers re: a method of glazing powder 1903 (Box-folder 17:10)
    - Correspondence with Charles Mane re: processing gunpowder, includes a stock list 1902-1903 (Box-folder 17:11)
    - Correspondence and patent re: improvements in drying and glazing gunpowder [1865] 1902 (Box-folder 17:12)
    - Correspondence re: glazing gunpowder 1903 (Box-folder 17:13)
    - Patents for explosives 1903 (Box-folder 17:14)
    - French, British, and German patent certificates, also correspondence with the United States Patent Office re: glazing blasting powder 1903 (Box-folder 17:15)
    - Application for a patent for a method for glazing blasting powder 1903 (Box-folder 17:16)
    - Application for a patent for improving powder presses 1904 (Box-folder 17:17)
    - Mining lease and indenture between Gilpin County Land and Mines Co. and AId 1913 (Box-folder 17:18)
- General
  - Cherry Island: correspondence with architects re: construction and furnishing of Cherry Island 1928 (Box-folder 17:19)
  - Cherry Island: correspondence with Edward Canby May, architect, re: furnishings and fittings for the main bungalow and crew house, also includes a list of specifications for furniture for the servants' cottage 1927 (Box-folder 17:20)
  - Washington Bridge: correspondence of Alfred I. duPont, chairman of the Washington Bridge Commission 1921 (Box-folder 17:21)
  - Washington Bridge: clipping of the dedication of Washington Street Memorial Bridge 1922 (Box-folder 17:22)
  - Washington Bridge: executed contract n.d. (Box-folder 17:23)
  - White Eagle: "Specifications for interior finish work for residence of Alfred I. duPont, Esq. Roslyn L[ong I[sland]. Carrere and Hastings, Architects." n.d. (Box-folder 17:24)
- Printed Materials
  - General
    - Boston-Maine Railroad map n.d. (Box-folder 18:1)
    - Bound volume of Town and Country No. 3502, June 28, 1913 and No. 3519, October 25, 1913, includes an arcticle on Nemours (pp. 21-23) (Box-folder 18:2)
    - General Motors Annual Reports 1928-1937 (Box-folder 18:3)